董卓主演脱口秀
than anyone thought.
看，上周，特朗普的新闻秘书是这么说的。
As he last week, Trump's press secretary said this.
我有一条直接来自总统的消息，我引用一下，
I have a message directly from the president, and I quote,
based on the fact that there's a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not
“基于在不远的将来，
与伊朗的谈判有很大可能性 会发生，也可能不会发生。”
take place with Iran in the near future.
“与伊朗在不远的将来。”
“我将在未来两周内决定
I will make my decision whether or not to go within the next two weeks.
是否要动手。”
那本来是完美的。
That would have been perfect for me, because we would have been on vacation next week,
对我来说，因为我们下周就要去度假了，
那样我就完全不会知道发生了这些事。
and I wouldn't have known any of this was happening.
现在我得取消我
Now I'm going to have to cancel my reservation that sandals fordo.
在福尔多（伊朗核设施）的度假预约了。 （注：此为双关玩笑，福尔多是伊朗的核设施，不是度假胜地。）
（笑声）
但是在周六，就在周六，
But on Saturday, or just Saturday, or just Saturday,
就在周六，特朗普震惊了
and Saturday, Trump surprised the world, announcing that the U.S.
全世界，宣布美国对伊朗的
launched strikes on three Iranian nuclear facilities.
三个核设施发动了空袭。
那么，我们是否面临着迫在眉睫的威胁？
Now, were we facing an imminent threat?
我不知道。
I don't know.
一方面，伊朗的口号可不是“美国万岁”。
On one hand, Iran's slogan isn't life to America,
但另一方面，很难相信唐纳德·特朗普是那个
but it's hard to trust Donald Trump to be the one making these kinds
能做这类决定的人。
of decisions. It kind of feels like we're all in the backseat
感觉就像我们都坐在后座，
而我们的优步司机正在路上开斗气车。
while the Uber driver goes on a road rage.
“嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，老兄，我们也在车里呢，好吗？”
Hey, hey, hey, hey, buddy, we're in the car, too, okay?
“如果我们死了，可就没法给你五星好评了。”
And if we're dead, we can't give you five stars.
这是我的...
That's my...
这是我给司机评分的铁律。
That is my heart rule for rating drivers.
我死了？
I'm dead.
零分。
No.
活着到达？
Arrival live?
我给五星。
I'm giving five.
周六晚些时候，特朗普向全国发表了几分钟的讲话，
Trump addressed the nation for a couple minutes later on Saturday night
并用一种极其古怪的方式结束了讲话。
and wrapped it up in just the weirdest way.
I want to just thank everybody, and in particular, God,
“我只想感谢所有人，特别是，”
“上帝，我只想说，我们爱你，上帝，”
I want to just say, we love you, God,
and we love our great military, protect them.
“我们爱我们伟大的军队，保护他们。”
Okay, it's a nice sentiment, you know,
好吧，这是个美好的祝愿，你知道的，
but a weird way to say it.
但说的方式很奇怪。
Yes, I have always been a devout believer in God.
“是的，我一直都是上帝虔诚的信徒。”
We love you, God. I know.
“我们爱你，上帝。”
“我知道我们关系不总是那么好，”
We haven't always been on the greatest terms since I made the deal
“自从我和那个在‘火焰林’里拿着‘波点叉’的家伙” （注：此为胡言乱语，模仿特朗普的讲话风格。）
with the guy with the Pokeyhead and the Flamenhoofs.
“做了交易之后。”
But point is, you rock, big guy.
“但重点是，你很酷，大家伙。”
Stay in school, have a great summer, Namaste.
“好好上学。”
“祝你暑假愉快，合十礼（Namaste）。”
（笑声）
LAUGHTER
Namaste.
合十礼。
在周日投下炸弹后，
CHEERING
After the bombs were dropped on Sunday,
Trump posted this message with a key misspelling.
特朗普发布了这条信息，其中有一个关键的拼写错误。
The great B-2 pilots have just landed safely in Missouri.
“伟大的B-2飞行员们刚刚在密苏里州安全着陆。”
Thank you for a job.
“感谢你们的工作。”
Well done.
“干得好。”
Donucked J-Trump.
“多纳克·J·特朗普（Donucked J. Trump），美利坚合众国总统。” （注：“Donucked”是“Donald”的拼写错误。）
President of the United States. Yes.
是的。
CHEERING
Yes.
好吧。
耶。
Yes.
是的。
多纳克·J·特朗普，说得像个脑袋被“多纳克”了的人。
Donucked.
J-Trump. Spoken like a man who got Donucked in Denoggin.
We're learning more about the actual bombing, the attack plan.
我们正在了解更多关于这次轰炸的细节，攻击计划。
It's codename Operation Midnight Hammer.
代号是“午夜战锤行动”。
And no, it's not porn.
不，这不是色情片。
LAUGHTER
（笑声）
Yet.
暂时还不是。
LAUGHTER
事情是这样的。
Here's what happened. In order to avoid detection, the plan was carried out
为了避免被发现，计划由
七架B-2隐形轰炸机执行。
by seven B-2 stealth bombers.
And I'm, is this true? I'm told we have a picture of the stealth planes.
而且我，这是真的吗？
我被告知我们有隐形飞机的照片。 （注：此处为视觉笑话，屏幕上什么都没有。）
Wow!
哇。
They are good.
它们真的很强。
The plans were carrying 30,000-pound bombs known as bunker busters,
这些飞机携带了3万磅的炸弹，
被称为“地堡终结者”，官方名称是MOPs，
officially called mobs, or massive ordinance penetrators.
即“巨型穿透弹”（Massive Ordinance Penetrators）。
The most...
这是自“战斧巡航恍惚弹”以来，
most phallic-sounding weapon since the...
听起来最具阳具崇拜色彩的武器了。
Tomahawk cruise shunts.
So America spies must have truly compelling intelligence,
所以，美国的间谍们一定掌握了非常可信的情报，
indicating that Iran was close to building a nuclear weapon,
表明伊朗即将制造出核武器……
or...
或者并没有，因为美国的间谍说伊朗并没有
or not, because America spies that Iran wasn't.
Building a nuclear weapon.
在制造核武器。
OK. OK. Hold on. Are they sure?
好吧。
等等。
他们确定吗？
Maybe our top spies just didn't have time to do a thorough check,
也许我们的顶级间谍只是没时间做彻底的检查，
because they were too busy hanging off of a biplane.
因为他们正忙着挂在双翼飞机上呢。 （注：暗指《碟中谍》电影情节。）
LAUGHTER
But, if the intelligence wasn't there, how did Trump decide it was time
但如果情报不存在，
特朗普是如何决定是时候攻击伊朗的
to attack Iran's nuclear program?
核计划的？
Well, according to a senior administration official,
嗯，据一位政府高级官员说，
it was based on a feeling...
这“基于总统的一种感觉”。
the president had.
If you are making a decision that could endanger the lives
如果你要做一个可能会
危及美国军队和平民生命的决定，
of American troops and civilians, help me out.
帮我一下。
Legal scholars, what does that require?
法律学者们，这需要什么？
THEY CONFER
谢谢你。
Thank you. Thank you.
嘿，市长。
谢谢你。
Thank you. Thank you.
嘿，市长。
谢谢你。
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
感谢你的服务。
Thank you for your service.
也感谢那根手杖。
Thank you for that staff.
And remember, this is an America's first military industrial rodeo.
记住，这不是美国军工复合体的
第一次牛仔竞技。
I've been making jokes about whether or not we should be going
22年来，我一直在开玩笑
说我们是否应该去中东开战。
to war in the Middle East for 22 years.
I did jokes from the Middle East for the service people
我曾为中东的军人们讲过笑话，
who were sent into harm's way based on no credible intelligence.
他们就是因为那些不可信的情报而被派往险境的。
But I will say this.
但我得这么说。
I will say this, sure.
我得这么说。
当然，当然。
I will say this about the Bush administration.
关于布什政府，我得这么说。
至少他们还尊重我们，知道要对我们撒谎。
At least they respected us enough to lie to us.
Apparently, the Trump administration does not give a damn what we think.
显然，特朗普政府根本不在乎
我们怎么想。
They're not presenting any evidence.
他们不提供任何证据。
拜托，伙计们。
Just come on, guys.
至少也吓唬我们一下啊。
Just at least scare us a little.
I missed the days when Colin Powell went to the UN Security Council
我怀念科林·鲍威尔去联合国安理会，
激情地挥舞着一管“乡村时光”牌
and passionately waved a tube of country-time lemonade powder.
柠檬水粉末的日子。 （注：讽刺2003年鲍威尔在联合国展示“伊拉克大规模杀伤性武器证据”——一小瓶白色粉末。）
I mean, just that much, just that much of the powder
我是说，就那么点粉末，就那么点，
could have refreshed everyone in that building.
就足够让那栋楼里的每个人都精神焕发了。
I mean, Trump should be out there telling us
特朗普应该站出来告诉我们，
that Iran is hiding 50 tons of mustard gas on a turkey farm
伊朗在火鸡农场藏了50吨芥子气，
or 50 tons of mustard turkey on a gas farm
或者在加油站农场藏了50吨芥末火鸡，
or human animal hybrids or anything.
或者人兽杂交体，或者随便什么都行。
And just sell it with sizzle.
至少卖力地宣传一下啊。
这简直是懒政。
This is just lazy.
制作水准太低了。
It's got low production value.
想象一下，如果下一部《变形金刚》电影就说：
As imagine, if the next Transformers movie was just like,
“你知道吗？”
you know what?
“我们觉得这部里就让它们保持汽车形态吧。”
I think we're just going to state cars in this one.
用点心好吗！
Put some effort in.
我知道。
不，我生气了。
I'm mad.
这不是我，生气。
This isn't me, mad.
接下来会发生什么？
What's going to happen next?
无论接下来发生什么，你都知道他们
Whatever happens next, you know they're
会让JD·万斯上电视出洋相的。
going to make JD Vance go on TV and embarrass himself.
Because here's what he said on Sunday
因为这是他周日说的，
为了推销这场绝对不是战争的战争。
to sell this war that is definitely not a war.
美国现在和伊朗开战了吗？
Is the United States now at war with Iran?
不，我们没和伊朗开战。
No, we're not at war with Iran.
约翰，我们是在和伊朗的核计划开战。
John, war with Iran's nuclear program.
不，不。
Nope, nope.
事情不是这么运作的。
That's not how it works.
“亲爱的，我没有和史黛西出轨。”
Honey, I'm not cheating on you with Stacy.
“我是在和史黛西的某些部分出轨。”
I'm cheating on you with parts of Stacy.
非常有选择性。
Very selective.
（欢呼和掌声）
And yes.
是的。
And yes, we do call it Operation Midnight Hammer.
是的，我们确实把它叫做“午夜战锤行动”。
Then.
Pretty.
然后...
Okay.
Then JD Sauntered over to press the meat with Kristen Welker.
真...
好吧。
然后JD慢悠悠地走到《媒体见面会》和克里斯汀·韦尔克聊天。
What do you say to members of Congress
你对那些说总统单方面行动
who say it was unconstitutional for the president
是违宪的国会议员
to act unilaterally?
有什么要说的？
首先，总统有明确的权力
First of all, the president has clear authority
采取行动防止大规模杀伤性武器的
to act to prevent the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction
扩散。
而其中最糟糕的大规模杀伤性武器
and the worst weapon of mass destruction of them all is nuclear.
就是核武器。
有待商榷。
Debatable.
依我之见，最糟糕的大规模杀伤性武器
From my money, the worst weapon of mass destruction
是塔可钟的三层玉米饼。
is the Taco Bell Tripleupa.
（笑声）
如果这一切感觉似曾相识，
If this all feels like deja vu, Vance promises,
万斯保证，这次不一样。
this time is different.
我当然同情那些在过去25年里
I certainly empathize with Americans who are exhausted
因中东的海外纠葛而疲惫不堪的美国人。
after 25 years of foreign entanglements in the Middle East.
但不同之处在于，那时候，
But the difference is that back then, we had dumb presidents.
我们有的是愚蠢的总统。
是的。
Yes.
那时候...
Back then.
他说得有道理。
He's got a point.
那时候，我们有的是愚蠢的总统。
Back then, we had dumb presidents.
而现在，我们有的是“多纳克·J·特朗普”。
And now we have Donak J. Trump.
Yeah.
（笑声）
（欢呼和掌声）
And more than that.
还有另一个...
Thank you, guys.
谢谢你们。
It was very nice.
非常感谢。
（欢呼和掌声）
Yeah.
他...
He is smart.
他很聪明。
（笑声）
You'll remember back in 2003, the US went into Iraq
你会记得，在2003年，美国入侵伊拉克
的具体目标是推翻萨达姆·侯赛因。
with the specific goal of toppling Saddam Hussein.
This time, Vance promises, that's not the idea.
这一次，万斯保证，
想法不一样。
Does the United States support Israel killing Iran's leader?
美国是否支持以色列刺杀伊朗领导人？
Well, look, that's up to the Israelis.
嗯，看，那是以色列人自己的事，
But our view has been very clear that we don't want a regime change.
但我们的观点一直很明确，我们不希望政权更迭。
OK.
好的，响亮而明确，
Great.
Loud and very clear and immediately contradicted by the president,
然后立刻被总统反驳了，他发帖说：
who posted, it's not politically correct to use the term regime change.
“使用‘政权更迭’这个词在政治上是不正确的。”
But if the current Iranian regime is unable to make Iran great again,
“但如果当前的伊朗政权不能让伊朗再次伟大...”
why wouldn't there be a regime change?
“为什么不能有政权更迭呢？”
Miga.
“让伊朗再次伟大（MIGA）。” （注：MIGA是“Make Iran Great Again”的缩写，戏仿特朗普的“MAGA”。）
（笑声）
Miga.
MIGA？
什么？
MIGA，你整个的核心理念是“美国优先”。
Because your whole damn thing is America first.
你不能把你的口号随便送给其他国家。
You can't just hand other countries your slogan.
那就好比麦当劳的广告说：
That's like if McDonald's had an ad campaign that said,
“我就喜欢，我喜欢的是汉堡王。”
I'm loving it, it being Burger King.
（笑声）
No.
不。
我生气了。
I'm mad.
不。
No.
天哪，真要命。
God bless it.
（欢呼和掌声）
Sorry, you had to see it.
抱歉，让你们看到了。
那是什么？
Let it out.
发泄出来，发泄出来。
Today, a Ron launched missiles against two U.S. bases,
今天，伊朗向两个美军基地发射了导弹，
including one in Qatar, but both Qatar and the Trump administration
其中一个在卡塔尔，但卡塔尔和特朗普政府
were made aware of the Iranian attack ahead of time.
都提前得到了伊朗袭击的通知。